<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-06T19:39:35+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Free Thinker</title><subtitle>Clean, concise thoughts on technology and economics.
</subtitle><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><entry><title type="html">Say no to maximalism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/09/06/say-no-to-maximalism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Say no to maximalism" /><published>2024-09-06T11:35:40+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-06T11:35:40+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/09/06/say-no-to-maximalism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/09/06/say-no-to-maximalism.html"><![CDATA[<p>Maximalism is the mindset that your project is the only valid one. This approach leads to a refusal to consider new information. It is dogmatic and somewhat intellectually limiting, in my opinion. And I have encountered it several times in the Bitcoin space.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Bitcoin maximalists tend to dismiss the perspectives of those outside Bitcoin. While I respect the economic tenets of Bitcoin, such as digital scarcity, the superiority complex should not overshadow technical discussions. Bitcoin is not inherently superior to other cryptocurrencies like Monero or Litecoin; it simply has its own trade-offs.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>However, there’s more to consider. Bitcoin embodies the free-market ideals envisioned by Austrian economists, who would likely support a market of competing currencies. To me, that means Bitcoin <em>embraces</em> this variety of cryptocurrencies. Being a Bitcoin maximalist is actually contrary to the spirit of Bitcoin, because it involves unwavering support for Bitcoin, when you should be skeptical and rigorous in examining its potential weaknesses. We move forward in life by addressing our flaws, not by celebrating our achievements. As Charles Darwin said,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It is not the strongest of the species that survive, nor the most intelligent, but the one most responsive to change.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><br />
Don’t be myopic and dogmatic. Say no to maximalism.</p>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maximalism is the mindset that your project is the only valid one. This approach leads to a refusal to consider new information. It is dogmatic and somewhat intellectually limiting, in my opinion. And I have encountered it several times in the Bitcoin space.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Conway’s game of life in C++</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/26/game-of-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Conway’s game of life in C++" /><published>2023-11-26T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-11-26T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/26/game-of-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/26/game-of-life.html"><![CDATA[<div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Under construction...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The game of life is a no-player <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_Game_of_Life#Undecidability">undecidable turing-complete</a> game with the following rules:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A live cell with less than two neighbours dies (as if by underpopulation).</li>
  <li>A live cell with two or three neighboors live on to the next generation.</li>
  <li>A live cell with more than three neighbours dies (as if by overpopulation).</li>
  <li>A dead cell with exactly three live neighbours is reborn (as if by reproduction).</li>
</ul>

<p>It is envisioned running in a 2D orthogonal grid universe which expands to infinity. But for the scope of this implementation, we’ll have to limit ourselves in the non-infinite amount of resources we possess in the real world. Therefore, we will shrink Conway’s Universe to a 211x56 matrix which can fit up to 11,816 cells.</p>

<p align="center">
  <img src="/resources/gameoflife.gif" width="100" alt="Alt Text" />
</p>
<p align="center">(example)</p>

<h1 id="classes">Classes:</h1>

<ul>
  <li>Cell: A cell object will be consisted of functions that let us know its living state (if it is alive or not), the total neighbours it currently has, <code class="highlighter-rouge">get</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">set</code> functions, and the respective constructor and destructor.</li>
  <li>Game: It will contain information such as at which generation we currently are and what the board looks like. When the user configures the initial state and runs the game, it will enter a loop where, in combination with <code class="highlighter-rouge">get</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">set</code> cell functions, it repeats the following algorithm:
    <ul>
      <li>Step 1: Check if there is a cell which must die as if by underpopulation. If there is, kill it and go to step 1.</li>
      <li>Step 2: Check if there is a cell which must die as if by underpopulation. If there is, kill it and go to step 1.</li>
      <li>Step 3: Check if there is a cell which must be reborn as if by reproduction. If there is, reborn it and go to step 1.</li>
      <li>Step 4: Inform the user that the game of life has ended.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Under construction...]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Your options to having privacy in Bitcoin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/15/options-of-privacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your options to having privacy in Bitcoin" /><published>2023-09-15T12:07:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-09-15T12:07:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/15/options-of-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/15/options-of-privacy.html"><![CDATA[<p>Due to recent events with <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-investigation-leads-takedown-darknet-cryptocurrency-mixer-processed-over-3">mixer being confiscated by authorities</a>, or <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?action=trust;u=3537433">mixer doing an exit scam</a>, or with a <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5389567.80">seemingly legitimate pro-privacy company going in the opposite direction</a>, I think a clarification of where we are at the moment in protecting the users’ privacy is necessary.</p>

<p>There are three ways to secure privacy of your bitcoins, each of which comes with its own advantages and disadvantages. Pick according to what fits you best.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <font size="5">CoinJoining</font>
    <p>There are three ways to do a <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/CoinJoin">coinjoin</a> with a large liquidity and effectively. Joinmarket, Whirlpool, and Wasabi. We’ll break down each.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<font size="4">1. Joinmarket</font>
<p>pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Decentralized; each of you can become your own coordinator if you provide sufficient liquidity. The protocol is designed to work with many takers (those that will take ordinary users’ offers).</li>
  <li>Self-custody.</li>
  <li>Large liquidity for coinjoins. (<a href="https://nixbitcoin.org/orderbook/">orderbook</a>)</li>
</ul>

<p>cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Difficult to setup for the average user.</li>
  <li>Expensive; you’re paying for the inputs of the takers. Those inputs are recommended to be more than 9, so you’ll be paying for at least a large in size transaction. This can be in the range of $5 to $10 sometimes.</li>
</ul>

<hr />
<p>‎</p>
<font size="4">2. Whirlpool</font>
<p>pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Self-custody.</li>
  <li>Very effective, contains <a href="https://bitcoin.clarkmoody.com/dashboard/">~8,500 BTC</a> in liquidity and you can make as many coinjoins as you want once you enter a pool.</li>
  <li>Cheap. For amounts within 0.001 and 0.025 BTC, you’re paying only 5,000 sat. For larger amounts less than 0.7 BTC, 50,000 sat. (mining fees asides)</li>
</ul>

<p>cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Not fundamentally decentralized; you’ll be using Samurai’s whirlpool, as they have the most liquidity.</li>
</ul>

<hr />
<p>‎</p>
<font size="4">3. Wasabi</font>
<p>pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Self-custody.</li>
  <li>Cheap. A fresh input (that isn’t already coinjoined) will only cost 0.3% of the amount with free remixes according to the wiki. (mining fees asides)</li>
</ul>

<p>cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Not decentralized. Liquidity sits on top of the default coordinator, even though it’s theoretically possible connect to other servers (none of which I’m aware of).</li>
  <li>Service treats the currency as non-fungible and might blacklist your inputs without rationale given.</li>
  <li>Software is caught to have flaws with protecting user’s privacy: <a href="https://twitter.com/wasabistats">https://twitter.com/wasabistats</a>.</li>
  <li>Funds blockchain analysis company and requests permission from them when user does coinjoin.</li>
</ul>

<hr />
<hr />
<p>‎</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <font size="5">Mixer services</font>
    <p>In this category falls every Internet service that runs individually. You can find an extended list in here: <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=2827109.0">2023 List Bitcoin Mixers Bitcoin Tumblers Websites</a>. Each service might come with other benefits, but they all fundamentally share the same pros and cons following:</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Can be cheap. In fact, some services in the past charged you absolutely nothing.</li>
  <li>Can be very effective. Services in the past used techniques like time travel and cutting of blockchain connection, both of which are impossible to do with coinjoins.</li>
</ul>

<p>cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>You’re forfeiting the custody of your coins.</li>
  <li>Trust that the service isn’t a honeypot or doesn’t keep logs is needed.</li>
</ul>

<hr />
<hr />
<p>‎</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <font size="5">Swapping bitcoin with a private cryptocurrency</font>
    <p>The third option is most likely underestimated. Swapping decentralized, cheaply, and with the largest anonymity set currently available (<a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero / XMR</a>), is attractive. Let’s look in each pro and con closely.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Decentralized, using <a href="https://bisq.network/">Bisq</a>, you can trade bitcoin for XMR, and there appear to be lots of offers: <a href="https://bisq.markets/market/xmr_btc">https://bisq.markets/market/xmr_btc</a></li>
  <li>Very effective; largest anonymity set (about $2.6B in <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/monero/">market cap</a>). You can also take advantage of the time; you can keep the XMR for an indefinite time, and make yourself even more untraceable.</li>
  <li>Self-custody. (if Bisq is used)</li>
  <li>No trust required. Monero is a network resulted from cryptographic achievements like ring signatures and their combination with confidential transactions.</li>
</ul>

<p>cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Might be a little complicated, as the user has to get along with Monero, and maybe even run a <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/downloads/">full node</a> for additional privacy.</li>
  <li>Might come a little more expensive sometimes. Total costs are: Bitcoin on-chain fees (<a href="https://bisq.wiki/Trading_costs">4 TXs</a>), Monero on-chain fees (nearly zero), Bisq fees (<a href="https://bisq.wiki/Trading_costs">trading costs</a>).</li>
  <li>You’re giving up bitcoin for an altcoin. Some may not like that, and if you keep it for a lot of time, there might be price fluctuations (which can be seen as an advantage too, as they randomize the swapped bitcoin amount).</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Due to recent events with mixer being confiscated by authorities, or mixer doing an exit scam, or with a seemingly legitimate pro-privacy company going in the opposite direction, I think a clarification of where we are at the moment in protecting the users’ privacy is necessary.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moving to: LineageOS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/16/lineageos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving to: LineageOS" /><published>2023-05-16T00:25:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-05-16T00:25:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/16/lineageos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/16/lineageos.html"><![CDATA[<div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Warning: author reviews an OS for the first time, be kind
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Have you ever felt like your smartphone spies on you? You know. When you’ve whispered some “top-level secret” which must not reach your cousin, roomate, sweetheart, or whatever; but it reaches your phone. And a little while later, you find a creepily accurate description on Facebook as “Suggested for you”, either as advertisement or just as post. Spooky coincidence, or crystal clear sign that your life is being scrutinized <em>to the bone</em>?</p>

<p>I have been a strong supporter of open-source, free software which is privacy-friendly, but I recently noticed I am overly focused on my computer, and I completely ignore the little spy I carry around in my pocket.</p>

<p>I was told that GrapheneOS was the most popular, privacy-respecting option, but unfortunately none of my two devices is suitable to install. So, I went with the second best option– <a href="https://lineageos.org/">LineageOS</a>.</p>

<h1 id="so-what-about-it">So what about it</h1>

<p>The OS isn’t privacy focused per se. It focuses on security and speed. As far as I understand, LineageOS developers have as hobby to improve the usability of old devices, by making them safer and faster. And indeed. My Xiaomi Redmi 7 was running as if it wasn’t 4 years old, with both <a href="https://wiki.lineageos.org/gapps">Gapps</a> and without.</p>

<p>But the part which attracted me the most is the same as with Linux distros; open-sourceness. You really don’t know what’s going on behind the scenes of a pre-installed Googled Android device. Arguing that it does what it says is equally valid with arguing that it gives special permission to some apps in secret. In both cases, you don’t have the evidence.</p>

<p>I really don’t know what was the fault with the incident I described previously. I only know that it happened, and that I had given no permission to record my voice with no apps running and phone closed. It is serious enough to have me switching to alternatives.</p>

<p>LineageOS lets the user tune those very permissions. Does Google Maps request microphone permission? You have the option to either:</p>
<ul>
  <li>not give it.</li>
  <li>give it, but only at that time.</li>
  <li>give it, but only as long as it is running.</li>
  <li>give it, regardless of whether it is running or not.</li>
</ul>

<p>Two screenshots from said device:</p>

<p align="center">
  <img src="/resources/screenshot1.png" alt="Alt Text" />
</p>

<p>Privacy dashboard lets you know which app uses what:</p>

<p align="center">
  <img src="/resources/screenshot2.png" alt="Alt Text" />
</p>

<p>The recommended installation for best privacy comes with lack of Gapps, but we all know you’re not going to live without Google apps (including apps from Play Store), so be cautious with what permissions you grant.</p>

<p>All in all, it’s great OS. I’d really love it if it was available at newer models like <a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/xiaomi_redmi_note_11s-11335.php">Redmi 11S</a>, but it’s just not their path. They work on making old devices work like new. And they’re pretty much doing it neat for a work that is done as hobby, with no financial incentive.</p>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Warning: author reviews an OS for the first time, be kind]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Proof-of-Work vs. Proof-of-Stake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/pow-vs-pos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Proof-of-Work vs. Proof-of-Stake" /><published>2023-05-15T19:39:44+03:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T19:39:44+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/pow-vs-pos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/pow-vs-pos.html"><![CDATA[<p>This thread is a tribute to all the discussions that have been made regarding these two mechanisms. As a PoW enthusiast, I’d like to explain why PoS is an inferior mechanism for such protocol as it loses in both centralization and capability of producing consensus, two of which are necessary for an innovative kind of money of this character.</p>

<p>But, before I move onto anything, I think that it’s very important to understand what’s <em>centralization</em>. It can be described as:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>The action or process of bringing activities together in one place.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As you may get, centralization is a vague term and it’s nowadays misused either unwittingly or to favor benefits. One may say that Bitcoin is less centralized in contrast with an altcoin, because its hash rate is distributed more properly, but they’d also be as correct as one saying that it’s less centralized, because it has a better wealth distribution (no ICOs etc.). An other may say that few pools own the majority of the hash rate and hence, it’s centralized; they may disagree that centralization can be measured etc.</p>

<p>Therefore, we need to precise what exactly we’ll call centralization. My definition goes as following:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Centralization is the situation where few people (can) have a great affectation to the final outcome of our economy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So, the more something’s centralized, the more those few can affect it. They’re analogous values. These people can either be developers or regular users.</p>

<h1 id="proof-of-work"><strong>Proof of Work</strong></h1>
<p>How it works in theory: (With lottery tickets as metaphor)</p>

<ol>
  <li>Everyone can generate lottery tickets.</li>
  <li>Scratching those requires spending of computational power.</li>
  <li>There’s no way to know if a ticket is a winning one unless you scratch it.</li>
  <li>Each ticket has a rarity.</li>
  <li>If someone proves they scratched a ticket whose rarity was one-out-of-one-trillion, they essentially reveal that they have searched one trillion tickets on average.</li>
  <li>The network decides what rarity is required for a ticket to be a winning one.</li>
  <li>Whoever scratches such ticket gets a reward.</li>
  <li>The required rarity changes based on the frequency of the winners.</li>
</ol>

<h1 id="proof-of-stake"><strong>Proof of Stake</strong></h1>
<p>How it works in theory:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Owners of the cryptocurrency lock up their funds.</li>
  <li>They vote by proving their financial bond with a digital signature. The greater the bond, the more the votes.</li>
  <li>The block with the most votes is considered the valid one.</li>
</ol>

<hr />
<p> </p>

<p>A <em>valid</em> transaction is a transaction that complies with the consensus rules and has been included into a block. For example, if you try to spend a transaction output that has already been spent, then the transaction is invalid as it goes against the rules. Satoshi Nakamoto solved the double-spending problem in the following way:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Require all the transactions to go through a ledger. Any transaction that is not written in it is ignored.</li>
  <li>When there are two conflicting transactions, the “correct” one is the one that was published first.</li>
  <li>To determine time, you need a timestamp server.</li>
  <li>To have a timestamp server, rely on proof of work.</li>
</ul>

<p>That way you can ensure for the validity of the ledger, without being present all the time. Consensus takes place when the transaction ordering problem is resolved in a decentralized way. That’s essentially Bitcoin. That’s the Byzantine generals’ <em>concerted strategy</em>.</p>

<h1 id="why-proof-of-stake-cannot-produce-consensus"><strong>Why Proof of Stake cannot produce consensus</strong></h1>
<p>Punishment plays a big role in this system. Our wealth is protected solely from a game theory: One or more entities are discouraged to cheat. Why that happens? Well, besides that:</p>

<p><sub><sup>Quote from: bitcoin.pdf, Satoshi Nakamoto</sup></sub></p>
<blockquote>
  <p>The incentive may help encourage nodes to stay honest. If a greedy attacker is able to assemble more CPU power than all the honest nodes, he would have to choose between using it to defraud people by stealing back his payments, or using it to generate new coins. He ought to find it more profitable to play by the rules, such rules that favour him with more new coins than everyone else combined, than to undermine the system and the validity of his own wealth</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There’s also one thing our fellow forgot to mention (or emphasize): Energy. If one’s behavior is dishonest towards the network, they’re forced to pay for acquiring energy whether their attack is successful or not. <strong>They’re punished outside the system.</strong></p>

<p>This is not true in proof of stake and you’ll understand why that’s bad along the way. Nonetheless, there has to be a way to discourage cheaters, even if they’re punished within the system’s borders, and there is: Security deposits. Once nodes stake their money, the network can use those to punish them in case they misbehave.</p>

<p>While the mechanism uses the users’ money to avoid double-spending it suffers from the so-called “double-signing problem”. In other words, the system isn’t objective in broad terms:</p>

<p><sub><sup>Quote from: How I Learned to Love Weak Subjectivity, Vitalik Buterin</sup></sub></p>
<blockquote>
  <p>However, new nodes joining the network, and nodes that appear online after a very long time, would not have the consensus algorithm reliably protecting them. Fortunately, for them, the solution is simple: the first time they sign up, and every time they stay offline for a very very long time, they need only get a recent block hash from a friend, a blockchain explorer, or simply their software provider, and paste it into their blockchain client as a “checkpoint”. They will then be able to securely update their view of the current state from there.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Remember, we use consensus to ensure that a newbie who just installed a client, syncs without doubt of whether what they’re receiving is valid or not. Their node demands from the rest to send blocks, it verifies the validity of every block and transaction and it’ll initially reach to the last block of the chain with the most work. That’s essentially the purpose of consensus; to avoid having unreliable actors.</p>

<p>When it comes to unreliability, our newbie is definitely safe in the PoW environment, but not in the PoS’. You see, since there’s lack of objectivity, the weaknesses already seem to show up. If, say, one wanted to attack, they could gain much influence by liquidating their stake and proceeding to the abuse of their own keys. Any blocks that had been signed by them would be vulnerable and they’d have nothing to lose. That’s known as “<a href="https://ethereum.stackexchange.com/questions/2402/what-exactly-is-the-nothing-at-stake-problem">Nothing at stake problem</a>”.</p>

<p>PoS cryptocurrencies attempt to solve this problem by either punishing the attackers with the deposits’ loss if they sign another block during a particular period of time or by ignoring a block that is signed a certain period of time later. The problem is that you can only do the latter if you were there from the start. If you had your node syncing, you’d have no way to know which of the two identical blocks is the correct one. As I’ve already said <strong>to have a timestamp server you need to rely on proof of work.</strong></p>

<h1 id="why-proof-of-stake-centralizes-the-system"><strong>Why Proof of Stake centralizes the system</strong></h1>
<p>Because, the sources to contribute to the network aren’t available outside the system. The “underpinnings” are in the stakers’ fate. In proof of work, when you setup your ASICs and start mining you’re, intentionally or not, <em>subsidizing decentralization</em> as the rest of the miners suddenly have less power. The opposite happens in proof of stake: To acquire voting power you increase their gains.</p>

<hr />
<p> </p>

<p>From: <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5387588.0">bitcointalk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This thread is a tribute to all the discussions that have been made regarding these two mechanisms. As a PoW enthusiast, I’d like to explain why PoS is an inferior mechanism for such protocol as it loses in both centralization and capability of producing consensus, two of which are necessary for an innovative kind of money of this character.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/why.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why" /><published>2023-05-15T19:07:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T19:07:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/15/why.html"><![CDATA[<p>“The point of this blog” you might ask? Well, besides fun:</p>

<ul>
  <li>It improves communication and writing skills.</li>
  <li>It acts as repository to my knowledge.</li>
  <li>It improves technical skills, because the process of explaining complex concepts in simple terms reinforces my understanding. Also, “If you can’t explain something to a first year student, then you haven’t really understood.” - <a href="https://everything2.com/title/Richard+P.+Feynman">R. Feynman</a></li>
  <li>Networking.</li>
</ul>

<p>Ok, so the real question now: why “angelo dot one”? No particular reason.</p>

<p>Just as <a href="https://youtu.be/Y45aema4iyM?t=165">Vsauce</a>, “angelo.1” was randomly picked. Although instead of fakenamegenerator.com, I used a comparably inferior source of randomness; <del><a href="https://xkcd.com/221/">xkcd</a></del> human brain. If “angelo.1” does not seem random to you, then good. That’s the <a href="https://youtu.be/cyn2pHAzaYw">moral of the story</a>.</p>

<p><span style="color:grey">My name <em>is</em> Angelo btw.</span></p>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“The point of this blog” you might ask? Well, besides fun:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll true minimal theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/jekyll-true-minimal-theme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll true minimal theme" /><published>2018-01-01T22:22:40+02:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T22:22:40+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/jekyll-true-minimal-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/01/jekyll-true-minimal-theme.html"><![CDATA[<p>True minimal theme is extremely lightweight and ascetic jekyll theme.</p>

<p>This theme has only one css file, which is used for source code highlighting.</p>

<h1 id="heading-1">Heading 1</h1>
<h2 id="heading-2">Heading 2</h2>
<h3 id="heading-3">Heading 3</h3>

<p>List of entries:</p>

<ul>
  <li>item 1</li>
  <li>item 2</li>
  <li>item 3</li>
  <li>item 4</li>
</ul>

<p>Source code are highlighted:</p>

<div class="language-perl highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">#!/usr/bin/perl</span>

<span class="k">sub </span><span class="nf">print_hello</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="k">print</span> <span class="p">"</span><span class="s2">Hello, Jekyll!</span><span class="se">\n</span><span class="p">";</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="nv">print_hello</span> <span class="nv">why</span> <span class="nv">isnt</span> <span class="nv">it</span> <span class="nv">working</span><span class="p">;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name>Angelo M.</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[True minimal theme is extremely lightweight and ascetic jekyll theme.]]></summary></entry></feed>